Inventory of the Arthur B. Nolan Pan American Airlines transpacific flight photographs, 1934-1938
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Arthur B. Nolan Pan American Airlines transpacific flight photographs
1934-1938
Nolan, Arthur B.
02665
.10 cubic ft. (1 small collection envelope)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Photographs of Pan American Airlines's first transpacific flight (1935), centering on Guam.
Arrangement of the Collection
Biography of Arthur B. Nolan
Arthur B. Nolan was a Pan American Airlines radio operator. He was a member of the crew that constructed radio stations to guide planes across the Pacific and was stationed in Guam in 1934-1935. Pan American Airlines' China Clipper made its first transpacific crossing in November-December, 1935. The Martin M-130 flew from California to Manila and back. Stops were made at Honolulu, Midway, Wake, and Guam.
Scope and Content
The collection contains photographs and other material from a scrapbook about the Pan American Airlines' first transpacific expedition. Most of the photographs were taken by Arthur B. Nolan in 1934-1935.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by Arthur B. Nolan at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
This material was received from Arthur B. Nolan in 1968
Access Terms
Pan American World Airways, Inc.; China Clipper (Airplane); Transpacific flights; Air mail service;; Guam
Transportation; Science, Technology and Health; Technology; Photographs
Container List
- Air Mail Cover and Other Printed Material, 1935 (Folder 1)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1935-1938 (Folder 2)
- Photographs - Guam, 1934-1935 (Folder 3)
- Photographs - Guam or Unidentified Place, 1934-1935 (Folder 4-5)
- Photographs - Midway, 1934-1935 (Folder 6)
- Photographs - Nolan, Arthur B., 1934-1935 (Folder 7)
- Photographs - S.S. North Haven, 1934-1935 (Folder 8)
- Photographs - San Francisco, 1935 (Folder 9)
- Photographs - Wake, 1934-1935 (Folder 10)
- Postcards - Honolulu, circa 1930s (Folder 11)